A FAST FORWARD MUSIC COMEDY.
Tapeheads is a comedy, drama, music film directed by Bill Fishman.
The story of Ivan and Josh, two dimwitted
ex-security guards who love music videos.
Out of work, with no job prospects, they form a music video production company.
They soon learn the ins and outs of the business in LA, and with
some help from Mo Fuzz, they soon become hot property.
But not all goes smoothly when they try to resurrect the career
of their favorite R&B duo, the Swanky Modes.
Ivan Alexeev, played by John Cusack.
Josh Tager, played by Tim Robbins.
Samantha Gregory, played by Mary Crosby.
Norman Mart, played by Clu Gulager.
Belinda Mart, played by Katy Boyer.
Kay Mart, played by Jessica Walter.
Tapeheads is a 1988 comedy film directed by Bill Fishman and starring John Cusack, Tim Robbins, Clu
Gulager, Doug McClure, Jessica Walter,  Mary Crosby, Sam Moore and Junior Walker.
The film was produced by Michael Nesmith, who briefly
appears as a bottled water delivery man.
The film premiered at the U.S.
Film Festival on January 22, 1988, with De Laurentiis Entertainment Group
attached as distributor and a tentative release date of March 1988.
However, due to financial concerns, distribution rights reverted to
NBC Productions, which sold them to Avenue Pictures.
The film was ultimately released on October 21, 1988 and was pulled
from theaters only two weeks into its theatrical run.
A poll of theater patrons by Avenue concluded that the film's underperformance could be attributed to the company's marketing
campaign, which was described as "too hip and selective" and aimed to promote the film as more of a slapstick comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.